Guide to the John B. Oakes Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Westmorland, Gen. William To John Bertram Oakes, Macoi, Vietnam, 3 April 1967, (1 t.l.s. (photocopy) ) (Box 4)
  - Whipple, Charles To John Bertram Oakes, [v.p.], 17 June 1975-17 Dec. 1981, (8 t.l.s. (with carbon replies and related material) ) (Box 4)
  - White, Theodore To John Bertram Oakes, New York, 19 Dec. 1977, (1 t.l.s. ) (Box 4)
  - Whitney, John Hay To John Bertram Oakes, New York, 26 April 1961-7 June 1965, (2 t.l.s. ) (Box 4)
  - Wiesel, Elie To John Bertram Oakes, Boston, 25 March 1994, (1 a.l.s. (photocopy) ) (Box 4)
  - Wilkins, Roger To John Bertram Oakes, New York, 23 Jan. 1974-29 April 1987, (3 a.l.s. (with carbon replies and related material) 2, t.l.s. (with carbon replies and related material) ) (Box 4)
  - Williams, G. Mennen To John Bertram Oakes, Lansing, MI. & Washington, D.C., 16 Dec. 1949-22 Aug. 1962, (3 t.l.s. ) (Box 4)
  - Wirth, Timothy To John Bertram Oakes, New York & Washington, D.C., 19 Oct. 1979-5 Aug. 1994, (7 a.l.s. (with carbon replies) 1, a.n.s. 7, t.l.s. (with carbon replies) ) (Box 4)
  - Wolfensohn, James D. To John Bertram Oakes, New York, 22 April 1991, (1 t.l.s. ) (Box 4)
  - You, Jong Keun To John Bertram Oakes, Alexandria, VA., 6 Jan. 1986, (1 t.l.s. ) (Box 4)
- Series II: Arranged Correspondence
  - Subseries II.1: Personal Correspondence Special Files
    - Albright, Horace (Box 5)
    - Avis (Box 5)
    - Balakian, Nora (Box 5)
    - Barlow, Elizabeth (Box 5)
    - Benton, William (Box 5)
    - Berman, Howard A. (Box 5)
    - Bernstein, Robert L. (Box 5)
    - Block, Sam (Box 5)
    - Brower, David (Box 5)
    - Brown, David W. (Box 5)
    - Buttenweister (Box 5)
    - Cahn, Robert (Box 5)
    - Carey, William (Box 5)
    - Casey Jr., William E. (Box 5)
    - Cashin, Bonnie (Box 5)
    - Curtis, Clifton E. (Box 5)
    - Eddy, Ted (Box 5)
    - Edey, Mitland A. (Box 5)
    - Eyton, Walter (Box 5)
    - Flack, Mamie Shaw (Box 5)
    - Forrester, Steve (Box 5)
    - Franklin, George (Box 5)
    - Friele, Berent (Box 5)
    - Gardner, Meredith (Box 5)
    - Gilbert, Daniet (Box 5)
    - Gross, Lawrence L (Box 5)
    - Growald, Eileen (Box 5)
    - Halle, Gorger (Box 5)
    - Halperin, Jonathan J. (Box 5)
    - Harmer (Box 6)
    - Harris, Gen. William A. (Box 6)
    - Hartwell, Sam (Box 6)
    - Hays Howard H.C. “Tim” (Box 6)
    - Hewitt, Patricia (Box 6)
    - Hiles, Clay (Box 6)
    - Hochschild, Adam (Box 6)
    - Holden, Arthur (Box 6)
    - Holmberg, Ruth S. (Box 6)
    - Hooper, Sir Robin and Lady (Box 6)
    - Hough, Henry Beetle (Box 6)
    - Jolles (Box 6)
    - Jones/Tifft (Box 6)
    - Kathy (Box 6)
    - Kocher, Mrs. Eric (Box 6)
    - Koopman, George (Box 6)
    - Kurman, Mitch (Box 6)
    - Lawrenceville Medal (Box 7)
    - Lennon, Thomas (Box 7)
    - Loucheim, Katie (Box 7)
    - McGowan, Carl (Box 7)
    - McKeever, Porter (Box 7)
    - Miller, Wm J. (Box 7)
    - Nathan, Adele Gutman (Box 7)
    - Nalzsky, Victor (Box 7)
    - Neal, Fred Warner (Box 7)
    - Newberg, Don (Box 7)
    - Oklavee, Mrs. Frank (Box 7)
    - Palmer, Nancy Reasoner (Box 7)
    - Pan Am (Box 7)
    - Potter, Robert S. (Box 7)
    - Prichard, Edward F. (Box 7)
    - Quinson, Bruno (Box 7)
    - Ramsbotham (Box 7)
    - Reede, Nathaniel P. (Box 7)
    - Rothschild, Lord Victor (Box 7)
    - Sharp, Peter (Box 7)
    - Sharry, Adelaide (Box 7)
    - Sheldon, Walter A. (Box 7)
    - Silver, Gordon (Box 7)
    - Sleeth, Charles (Box 7)
    - Squyers, Debbie (Box 7)
    - Stone, Shepard (Box 7)
    - Thacher, Thos (Box 7)
    - Time Inc (Box 7)
    - Werner, Anne Simon Nan (Box 7)
    - Werner, Walter (Box 7)
    - Yoakum, Robert (Box 7)
    - Yost, Nicholas (Box 7)
    - Zweite, Armin (Box 7)
  - Subseries II.2: New York Times Correspondence
    - Adams, Frank S. (Box 8)
    - Argyris, C (Box 8)
    - Balkian, Nora (Box 8)
    - Baldwin, Hanson (Box 8)
    - Bancroft, Harding 1972-1973/5 (Box 8)
    - Barzilay, Robert (Box 8)
    - Bendiner, Robert (Box 8)
    - Borland, Hal (Box 8)
    - Brown, James P. (Box 9)
    - Carrletern (Box 9)
    - Curtis, Charlotte (Box 9)
    - Duffus, Robert L. (Box 9)
    - Durdin, Tillman (Box 9)
    - Daniel, Clifton (Box 9)
    - Daniels, E.C. (Box 9)
    - De Liberto, Vincent (Box 9)
    - Epstein, Mark (Box 9)
    - Flint, Peter (Box 9)
    - Gelb, Arthur (Box 9)
    - Goldberg, Howard (Box 9)
    - Goldenstein, Nathan (Box 9)
    - Goodale, James C. (Box 9)
    - Grose, Peter (Box 9)
    - Gruson, Sydney (Box 9)
    - Hamilton, John A. (Box 9)
    - Hauk, Eric (Box 10)
    - Haulsey, James (Box 10)
    - Hechinger, Fred M. (Box 10)
    - Hovey, Graham (Box 10)
    - Huxtable, Ada Louise (Box 10)
    - Jacoby, Bill (Box 10)
    - Kleiman, Robert (Box 10)
    - Kleiman, Robert 2 (Box 11)
    - Lawrence, William L (Box 11)
    - Lewis, Anthony (Box 11)
    - Lewis, Flora (Box 11)
    - Mattson, Walter 1974-76 (Box 11)
    - Maynard, Joyce (Box 11)
    - Merz, Charles (Box 11)
    - Mitgang, Herbert (Box 11)
    - Mossien, Edward A. (Box 11)
    - Ogden, William D. (Box 11)
    - Peters, Richard (Box 11)
    - Pomerantz (Box 12)
    - Pomfret, John/ McCabe, John (Box 12)
    - Raines, Howell (Box 12)
    - Rodvogen, Carol (Box 12)
    - Rosenthal, A.M. (Box 12)
    - Rossant, Murray J. (Box 12)
    - Reston, James (Box 12)
    - Schanberg, Sydney H. (Box 12)
    - Schneiderman, David (Box 12)
    - Schwartz, Henry (Box 12)
    - Schwarz, David (Box 13)
    - Segal, Harvey (Box 13)
    - Seigel, Kalman (Box 13)
    - Semple, Robert (Box 13)
    - Shaffer, Marylou (Box 13)
    - Silk, Leonard (Box 13)
    - Suares, Jean-Claude S. (Box 13)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur Jr. (Box 13)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur Ochs: Compensation (Box 13)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur Ochs: Content (Box 13)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur Ochs: Controversy (Box 14)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur Ochs: General Memos 1963-1973 (Box 14)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur Ochs: General Memos 1974-1992 (Box 14)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur Ochs: NYT Advertising Policy (Box 14)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur Ochs: Transition 1976 (Box 15)
    - Tolischus, Otto D. (Box 15)
    - Topping, Seymour (Box 15)
    - Transport Workers Union of America (Box 15)
    - Van Doorn, John (Box 15)
    - Veit, Ivan (Box 15)
    - Webster, Bayard (Box 15)
    - Wicker, Tom (Box 15)
  - Subseries II.3: New York Times Op-Ed Correspondence
    - Letters to the Editor 1951-1969 (3) (Box 16)
    - Agnew Letters 1968 (Box 16)
    - Letters to the Editor 1970-1973 (Box 16)
    - Letters to the Editor 1974-3/30/74 (Box 16)
    - Letters to the Editor 1975 (Box 17)
    - Responses to Letters 1975 (Box 17)
    - Chronological File 6/1/78-12/31/78 (Box 17)
    - Letters to the Editor 1976-1982 (Box 17)
    - Letters to the Editor (Eccentric/Threatening) (Box 17)
    - NY Times 1971-1972 (Box 17)
    - NY Times Important (Box 17)
    - NY Times Memos and Correspondence (Box 17)
    - Op-Ed Acknowledgements (Box 17)
    - Op-Ed Proposed, February 1975 (Box 17)
    - Op-Ed Responses, Feb 1984 (Box 17)
    - Op-Ed Writing (General Letters to JBO) (Box 17)
  - Subseries II.4: General Correspondence
    - E (Box 18)
    - F (Box 18)
    - J (Box 18)
    - S (Box 18)
    - A, 1950-1964 (Box 18)
    - B, 1950-1960 (Box 18)
    - C, 1950-1960 (Box 18)
    - D, 1955-1964 (Box 18)
    - E, 1955-1961 (Box 18)
    - F, 1951-1969 (Box 18)
    - G, 1950-1964 (Box 18)
    - H, 1950-1964 (Box 18)
    - K, 1962-1965 (Box 18)
    - M, 1961-1968 (Box 18)
    - R, 1957-1971 (Box 18)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 18)
    - T, 1966-1967 (Box 18)
    - F-H, 1970-1971/2 (Box 18)
    - K, 1970-1971/2 (Box 18)
    - C, 1973-1974/5 (Box 18)
    - I, 1973-1974/5 (Box 18)
    - O, 1973-1974/5 (Box 18)
    - S, 1973-1974/5 (Box 18)
    - U, 1973-1974/5 (Box 18)
    - B-C, 1976-7 (Box 18)
    - F-M, 1976-7 (Box 18)
    - O-P, 1976-7 (Box 18)
    - R, 1976-7 (Box 18)
    - T, 1967-7 (Box 18)
    - V-XYZ, 1976-7 (Box 18)
    - A-K, 1978-1979 (Box 18)
    - L-XYZ, 1978-1979 (Box 19)
    - A-P, 1980-1981 (Box 19)
    - R-T, 1980-1981 (Box 19)
    - W, 1980-1981 (Box 19)
    - Y-Z, 1980-1981 (Box 19)
    - A-J, 1982-1983 (Box 19)
    - K, 1982-1983 (Box 19)
    - M-N, 1982-1983 (Box 19)
    - P, 1982-1983 (Box 19)
    - R-T, 1982-1983 (Box 19)
    - W, 1982-1983 (Box 19)
    - B-H, 1984-1985 (Box 20)
    - K-P, 1984-1985 (Box 20)
    - R-U, 1984-1985 (Box 20)
    - W-XYZ, 1984-1985 (Box 20)
    - Business Correspondence A-Z (Box 21)
  - Subseries II.5: Personal Correspondence
    - A1 Abel - Andrasco (Box 22)
    - A2 Andrus - Azrael (Box 22)
    - B1 Bach – Bengalloun (Box 22)
    - B2 Bennett – Borsody (Box 22)
    - B3 Botein – Browne (Box 22)
    - B4 Brucker – Byrne (Box 23)
    - C1 Caen – Clirman (Box 23)
    - C2 Cockburn – Core (Box 23)
    - C3 Cotten – Currey (Box 23)
    - D1 D’Addario – Dilworth (Box 24)
    - D2 Ditchley – Dyson (Box 24)
    - E1 Eastman – Erler (Box 24)
    - E2 Ernst – Ezcurra (Box 24)
    - F1 Fanning – Fischer (Box 24)
    - F2 Fisher – Fuller (Box 25)
    - G1 Galvin – Gifford (Box 25)
    - G2 Gilhooly – Gores (Box 25)
    - G3 Gottschalk – Gustavson (Box 25)
    - H1 Haight - Hartman (Box 25)
    - H2 Harvey – Hemmendinger (Box 25)
    - H3 Herbert – Hofman (Box 26)
    - H4 Hohenberg – Hyde (Box 26)
    - I Iloniemi – Istel (Box 26)
    - J Jackett- Jovan (Box 26)
    - K1 Kam – Killingworth (Box 26)
    - K2 Kim – Kwitny (Box 26)
    - L1 Labalme – Lennon (Box 26)
    - L2 Lese – Lincoln Center (Box 26)
    - L3 Lindsay – Lyons (Box 27)
    - M1 MacIntire – Meacham (Box 27)
    - M2 Mead – Myerson (Box 27)
    - N Nason – Nuriman (Box 27)
    - O Oaks – Owens (Box 27)
    - P1 Packard – Picker (Box 28)
    - P2 Pidgeon – Purner (Box 28)
    - R1 Rabb – Roche (Box 28)
    - R2 Rodgers – Rostow G. (Box 28)
    - R3 Rostow W – Ryan (Box 28)
    - S1 Sacerdoti – Schor (Box 28)
    - S2 Scott – Shanks (Box 29)
    - S3 Sharp – Sonne (Box 29)
    - S4 Sorensen – Symington (Box 29)
    - T Talese – Tyson (Box 29)
    - U Udall- United Jewish Appeal (Box 29)
    - V Vanden – Von Klemperer (Box 29)
    - W1 Wainwright – Wheeler (Box 29)
    - W2 White - Wilson (Box 29)
    - W3 Winship – Wyazanski (Box 30)
    - Y Yarn – Yost (Box 30)
    - Z Zaslowsky - Zuckerman (Box 30)
  - Subseries II.6: Family and Personal
    - Sub-subseries II.6.1: John Oakes Correspondence
      - Adler, Ada (Box 31)
      - Adler, Ada Telegrams (Box 31)
      - Adler, Elmer (Box 31)
      - Adler, Harry (Box 31)
      - Adler, Harry Telegrams (Box 31)
      - Adler, Julius Ochs (Box 31)
      - Adler, Julius Ochs Telegrams (Box 31)
      - Adler, Mrs. Julius Ochs (Babs) (Box 31)
      - Alice (Box 31)
      - Allan, Rupert (Box 31)
      - Bennett, Chick (Box 31)
      - Berneis, Hans C. (Box 31)
      - Böker, Alexander (Box 31)
      - Bourbon, M.L. Bokey (Box 31)
      - Bowes, J.T. (Box 31)
      - Boyce, Gray C. (Box 31)
      - Brainard, William W. Jr. (Box 31)
      - Briggs, Doris (Box 31)
      - Briggs, Susan (Box 31)
      - Cary, William (Box 31)
      - Chudnowski, Walter (Box 31)
      - Coliver, Norman Cohen (Box 31)
      - Cowen, J. David (Box 31)
      - Cronan, Joe (Box 31)
      - Diana (Box 31)
      - Donovan, Hedley (Box 31)
      - Echrich, Adelaide, W. (Box 31)
      - Fenton (Box 31)
      - Finkelbaum, Tanya (Box 31)
      - Fischer, Elizabeth Wilson (Box 31)
      - Gans (Box 31)
      - Gans, Milton (Box 31)
      - Gans, Walter S. (Box 31)
      - Gaskill, Bill (Box 31)
      - Goodhart, Phyllis (Box 31)
      - Haller, Harry (Box 32)
      - Haller, Harry Telegrams (Box 32)
      - Haller, Kitty (Box 32)
      - Heckacher, Maury (Box 32)
      - Hochschild, Harold (Box 32)
      - Hooper, Robin (Box 32)
      - Hortense (Box 32)
      - Kermit (Box 32)
      - Kilralf-Heausler, Lori (Box 32)
      - Kuhn, Ferdie (Box 32)
      - Lethbridge, Kathleen (Box 32)
      - Lewi, Isador (Box 32)
      - Lewis, Weston (Box 32)
      - Lord, Betty Brereton (Box 32)
      - Macdonald of the Isles, Celia (Box 32)
      - McElroy, Robert (Box 32)
      - McGhee, George (Box 32)
      - Marshall, Pardee (Box 32)
      - Marshall, Pegge (Box 32)
      - Musso, Germaine (Box 32)
      - Nelson, John (Box 32)
      - Oakes, George, [n.d.] (Box 33)
      - Oakes, George, 1926-1935 (Box 33)
      - Oakes, George, 1936-1939 (Box 33)
      - Oakes, George, 1940-1944 (Box 33)
      - Oakes, George Telegrams (Box 33)
      - Oakes, Joanna Rose (Box 33)
      - Oakes, Joanna Rose Telegrams (Box 33)
      - Oakes, Margery Hartman (Box 33)
      - Oakes, Margery Hartman Telegrams (Box 33)
      - Ochs, Adolph S. (Box 33)
      - Ochs, Adolph S. Telegrams (Box 33)
      - Ochs, Effie (Box 33)
      - Ochs, Effie Telegrams (Box 33)
      - Ochs, Fan (Mrs. Milton Ochs) (Box 33)
      - Ochs, Hazel (Box 33)
      - Ochs, Milton (Box 33)
      - Ochs, Milton Telegrams (Box 33)
      - Ochs, Nan, [n.d.] (Box 33)
      - Ochs, Nan, 1929-1930 (Box 33)
      - Ochs, Nan, 1931-1936 (Box 34)
      - Ochs, Nan Telegrams (Box 34)
      - Ochs-Oakes, George Washington, 1924-1930 (Box 34)
      - Ochs-Oakes, George Washington, 1931\ (Box 34)
      - Ochs-Oakes, George Washington Telegrams (Box 34)
      - Ochs, William Van Dyke (Box 34)
      - Ochs, Mrs. William Van Dyke (Alice) (Box 34)
      - Okin, Bob (Box 34)
      - Page, Henry (Box 34)
      - Philpot, Margaret (Box 34)
      - Plant, Emmy Lou (Box 34)
      - Princeton-Root, Robert K. (Box 34)
      - Priest, George M. (Box 34)
      - Ralston, Pat (Box 34)
      - Reid, Mrs. William (Box 34)
      - Richert, Erni (Box 34)
      - Roberts, Victor J. (Box 34)
      - Rockefeller, Mrs. David (Peggy) (Box 34)
      - Rose, Dula (Box 34)
      - Rose, Peggy (Box 34)
      - Russell, P.E. (Box 34)
      - Sellon, Perry (Box 34)
      - Shaw, Maxine Farley (Box 35)
      - Sheldon, William (Bill) (Box 35)
      - Smith, Jim (Box 35)
      - Sulzberger, Arthur Hayes (Box 35)
      - Sulzberger, Arthur Hayes (Box 35)
      - Sulzberger, Mrs. Arthur (Iphigene) (Box 35)
      - Sulzberger, Marion (Box 35)
      - Sulzberger, Ruth (Box 35)
      - Sweetser, Ruth (Box 35)
      - Talimer, Bernie (Box 35)
      - Talimer, Mattie (Box 35)
      - Talimer, Mattie Telegrams (Box 35)
      - Van Dusen, Francis (Box 35)
      - Vuillamy, Patricia (Box 35)
      - Welles, Sam (Box 35)
      - Willeke, Frank (Box 35)
      - Wertenbaker, Sarah (Box 35)
      - Wertenbaker, T.J. (Box 35)
      - A-C (Box 36)
      - D-F (Box 36)
      - G-H (Box 36)
      - I-L (Box 36)
      - M (Box 36)
      - N-O (Box 36)
      - P-S (Box 36)
      - T-Z (Box 36)
      - Cards (Box 37)
      - Invitations (Box 37)
      - Unidentified Correspondence (Box 38)
    - Sub-subseries II.6.2: Nannie Oakes Correspondence
      - Adler, Ada (Box 39)
      - Adler, Julius Ochs (Box 39)
      - Adler, Julius Ochs Telegrams (Box 39)
      - Barbara (Box 39)
      - Deanie (Box 39)
      - Gans, Milton (Box 39)
      - Hayes, Christopher (Box 39)
      - Jenkins, Alice (Box 39)
      - Lewi, Isador (Box 39)
      - Nancy (Box 39)
      - Oakes, George (Box 39)
      - Oakes, George Telegrams (Box 39)
      - Oakes, Joanna Rose (Box 39)
      - Oakes, John, [n.d.] (Box 39)
      - Oakes, John, 1922-1928 (Box 39)
      - Oakes, John, 1929 (Box 39)
      - Oakes, John, 1930 (Box 39)
      - Oakes, John, 1931 (Box 39)
      - Oakes, John, 1932 (Box 39)
      - Oakes, John, 1933 (Box 39)
      - Oakes, John, 1934 (Box 40)
      - Oakes, John, 1935 (Box 40)
      - Oakes, John, 1936 Jan-June (Box 40)
      - Oakes, John, 1936 July-Dec (Box 40)
      - Oakes, John, 1937 Jan-Aug (Box 40)
      - Oakes, John, 1937 Sept-Dec (Box 40)
      - Oakes, John, 1938 Jan-June (Box 41)
      - Oakes, John, 1938 July-Dec (Box 41)
      - Oakes, John, 1939 (Box 41)
      - Oakes, John, 1940 (Box 41)
      - Oakes, John, 1941 (Box 41)
      - Oakes, John, 1942 (Box 41)
      - Oakes, John, 1943 (Box 41)
      - Oakes, John, 1944 (Box 41)
      - Oakes, John, 1945 (Box 41)
      - Oakes, John, 1946 (Box 41)
      - Oakes, John, 1947 (Box 41)
      - Oakes, John Telegrams (Box 42)
      - Oakes, Margery Hartman (Box 42)
      - Ochs, Adolph (Box 42)
      - Ochs, Alice (Box 42)
      - Ochs, Billy (Box 42)
      - Ochs, Effie (Box 42)
      - Ochs, Fan (Box 42)
      - Ochs, Julius (Box 42)
        [J.B.O.’s paternal grandfather]
      - Ochs, Milton (Box 42)
      - Ochs-Oakes, George Washington (Box 42)
      - Ochs-Oakes, George Washington Telegrams (Box 42)
      - Squier, Leah (Box 42)
      - Sulzberger, Mrs. Arthur Hayes (Iphigene) (Box 42)
      - Sulzberger, Arthur Ochs (Box 42)
      - Letters to Nannie Ochs (Alphabetical file) (Box 42)
      - Telegrams to Nannie Ochs (Box 42)
      - Business Letters (Box 42)
      - Unidentified Correspondence (Box 42)
    - Sub-subseries II.6.3: George Oakes Correspondence
      - Gans, Milton (Box 43)
      - Oakes, John (Box 43)
      - Ochs, Effie (Box 43)
      - Ochs, Nannie (Box 43)
      - Ochs-Oakes, George Washington (Box 43)
      - Talimer, Mattie (Box 43)
      - Letters to George Oakes (Alphabetical) (Box 43)
      - Telegrams (Box 43)
    - Sub-subseries II.6.4: Margery Hartman Oakes Correspondence
      - Oakes, John (Box 43)
      - Letters to Margery Hartman Oakes (Alphabetical) (Box 43)
      - George Washington Ochs-Oakes Correspondence (Box 43)
      - Letters to George Washington Ochs-Oakes (Alphabetical file) (Box 43)
    - Sub-subseries II.6.5: Other Family Correspondence
      - Other Family Correspondence (Box 43)
      - Letters to Other Family from John Oakes (Alphabetical file) (Box 43)
      - Letters to Other Family from Other Family (Alphabetical file) (Box 43)
      - Letters to Other Family from Non-Family (Alphabetical file) (Box 43)
      - Letters to Non-Family from Other Family (Alphabetical file) (Box 43)
      - Telegrams to Other Family (Box 43)
- Series III: Arranged Subject Files
  - Subseries III.1: New York Times General Files
    - Accounting (Box 44)
    - Advertising Policy/Correspondence (Box 44)
    - Affirmative Action Program (Box 44)
    - Alfred Knopf Book Project on “Best NYT Editorials” (Box 44)
    - Annual Reports (Box 44)
    - Art Department (Box 44)
    - Articles and Letters re: JBO Move to Senior Editor (Box 44)
    - Asahi Shinbun (Japan): Editorial Collaboration (Box 44)
    - Board of Directors Reports (Box 44)
    - Book Review (Box 44)
    - Booz, Allen, and Hamilton Office Services Project (Box 44)
    - Charitable Contributions (Box 44)
    - Carnegie Corporation Travel Grant (Box 45)
    - Composing Room Correspondence (Box 45)
    - Congressional Correspondence 1 (Box 45)
    - Congressional Correspondence 2 (Box 45)
    - Congressional Correspondence 3 (Box 46)
    - Editorial Department: Discussions of Editorial Page (Box 46)
    - Editorial Position on Everglades Tourism (1965 Controversy with Miami Herald) (Box 46)
    - Editorial Position on the New York Stock Exchange (Box 46)
    - Editorial Position on Press Monopoly (Box 46)
    - Editorial Reference Library (Box 46)
    - Education News Department: Search for Editor, 1958 (Box 46)
    - Electronic Editing Program (Box 46)
    - Financial New York Times, 1972-1978 (Box 46)
    - Financial New York Times, 1986, 1989-91 (Box 46)
    - Financial New York Times Expenses, 1958-1968 (2) (Box 46)
    - Foreign News Desk: Correspondence/ Story Suggestions by JBO (Box 47)
    - Governor’s Conferences, 1954, 1956, 1958 (Box 47)
    - Indianapolis Star: Controversy re: printed NYT editorial, 1968 (Box 47)
    - International Edition: Memos re: Editorial/Letters Policy (Box 47)
    - John Paul Vann: Letters from Vietnam (Box 47)
    - JBO Defense of NYT on Vietnam (Box 47)
      [See also Hansen Baldwin Corresp.]
    - JBO v. Edward Costikyan re: New York Magazine Article “Who Runs the City”, 1968 (Box 47)
    - JBO v. Edward Klein Re: Manhattan, Inc. article on GWOO (Box 47)
    - JBO v. Encounter Magazine re: Henry Faille article Press, 1966 (Box 47)
    - JBO Awards and Honors (Box 47)
    - Legal Department: Julius Ochs Adler Trusts (Box 47)
    - Letters Department: Also see Kalman Seigel, International Edition (2) (Box 47)
    - Letters of Complaint (JBO Responses) (Box 47)
    - McCarthy/McCarthyism: Grace Roosevelt-Iphigene Sulzberger-Pegler (Box 48)
    - Correspondence (Box 48)
    - McCarthy/McCarthyism: JBO Articles and Responses (Box 48)
    - McCarthy/McCarthyism: JBO and NYT Editorial Position (Box 48)
    - Management Reports: Publisher’s Confidential Reports (Box 48)
    - Metropolitan News Desk: Correspondence (w/A. Gelb), Story Suggestions by JBO (Box 48)
    - National Conference of Editorial Writers, 1955 (Box 48)
      [Notable for A.H.]
    - Sulzberger comment on NYT position re: race relations (Box 48)
    - National News Desk (story suggestions by JBO) (Box 48)
    - New Contract (1970) and Public Reaction to Times Settlement (Box 48)
    - News Bureaus: Correspondence with Timesmen/women (Box 48)
    - News Dept. Memos re: Policy/Story suggestions by JBO (Box 48)
    - Newspaper Guild (Box 48)
    - New York Times News Service (Box 48)
    - New York Times Vietnam Editorials (Box 48)
    - Op-Ed Advertising Policy (Box 49)
    - Op-Ed Art Exhibition in France, 1973-1974 (Box 49)
    - Op-Ed Memos re: Creation of Op-Ed page, 1966-1970 (Box 49)
    - Op-Ed Memos re: Proposed Disclaimer for Opinions on Page (Box 49)
    - Op-Ed Memos re: Functioning of Op-Ed page, 1970 (4) (Box 49)
    - Permissions Department (Box 50)
    - Poetry Department (Box 50)
    - Promotion/Public Relations Department (Box 50)
    - Pulitzer Prize Entries, 1961-1976 (Box 50)
    - Quadrangle (NYT Book Company) (Box 50)
    - Readership Surveys (Box 50)
    - Reports on Washington Trips: Interviews with Government Officials, 1950-1960 (Box 50)
    - Science Department (Box 50)
    - Serbelloni Conference, Italy, 7/25-29, 1965 (Box 50)
    - Society Department (Wedding Announcements) (Box 50)
    - Sports Department (Box 50)
    - Style Department (Memos Largely to/from Lewis Jordan) (Box 50)
    - Task Force Editorial Page, 1972 (Box 50)
    - Task Force: Final Report “How to Improve the Times”, 1972 (Box 51)
    - Task Force: Letters to the Editor (Editorial Page), 1972 (Box 51)
    - Task Force: News of the Week in Review, 1972 (Box 51)
    - Task Force: NYT Magazine, 1972 (Box 51)
    - Task Force: Op-Ed Page (Editorial Page), 1972 (Box 51)
    - Third Informal US-USSR Conference, Andover MA, 10/21-27, 1962 (Box 51)
    - Topics Column (includes unsolicited submissions) (Box 51)
    - White House Fellows (Box 51)
    - Woodrow Wilson Award Congratulatory letters and answers (Box 51)
    - WQXR-FM (Box 51)
  - Subseries III.2: Biographical Material: Education
    - Childhood/Youth/Collegiate/Lawrenceville (Box 52)
    - Report Books, Collegiate School (Box 52)
    - Summer Camp (Box 52)
    - Princeton (Box 52)
    - Princeton/Oxford (Box 53)
    - Princeton/Oxford (Box 53)
    - Oxford (Box 53)
    - Syracuse University Course (Box 53)
  - Subseries III.3: Biographical Material: Military Service
    - Army, 1951 (Box 54)
    - Army Records, 1948-1969 (Box 54)
    - Army JBO: 1941-1950 (Box 54)
    - Army/Military/OSS Service (WWII) (Box 54)
    - Army Service—Decorations (Box 54)
    - CIA File (Box 55)
  - Subseries III.4: Biographical Material: Documents and Notebooks
    - Passport (Box 56)
    - Driver’s License (Box 56)
    - Address Book (Box 56)
    - Notebook (Box 56)
  - Subseries III.5: Biographical Material: Photographs
    - Unsorted Photographs (Box 57)
  - Subseries III.6: Clubs, Awards, Honors, Etc.
    - Awards and Honors: Polk Award, Columbia-Catherwood Award (Box 58)
    - AAAs Committee on Environmental Alternatives (Box 58)
    - Adirondack Council/Commission on the Adirondacks (Box 58)